JIMMY SWANBECK

Address: 59 Howard Street #2, Cambridge, MA 02139

Email: jimmy.swanbeck@gmail.com

Cell: 978.319.1939

SUMMARY

Software engineer with development experience across multiple platforms. Quick learner with the motivation to self-teach new concepts and set them to practical application. Most experienced with web application development, but also passionate about cyber security and artificial intelligence with a general love of problem solving.

EDUCATION

Endicott College, Bachelor's Degree, Magna Cum Laude Computer Science, 2012 - 2015

University of Massachusetts Lowell

Biology, 2011 - 2012

SKILLS

Python, PHP, Javascript, jQuery, React, Docker, Git, Linux

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, BAE Systems Applied Intelligence

June 2015 - Present

- Test-driven development of BAE Systems' Secure Management Console (SMC) application (incorporating their entire cyber security product suite) in PHP and Javascript on a Symfony framework, utilizing object-oriented models to build a robust architecture that allows for scalability.
- ♦ Key role in the engineering of the new Managed Security Services (MSS) product. Responsible for the development of several brand new features and APIs as well as the overhaul / re-creation of legacy infrastructures.
- Design and implementation of data-driven microservices in Python to handle various internal data transfers, often integrating third party libraries and solutions.
- Employed Git workflows to partition development lines along major release and feature branches.
- Leveraged Docker for rapid prototyping of new services and containerization of existing services primarily developed on (and deployed to) hosts running various Linux distributions and releases.

Developer Intern, SilverSky / BAE Systems

June 2014 - May 2015

- Extension and implementation of SilverSky's Network Security Console (NSC) product line; authored an implementation of a single sign-on feature to integrate existing services into a "single pane of glass."
- Created python utilities for legacy customers' migration to a new platform; database targets included Oracle SQL, MySQL, and MSSQL; supported both command-line and REST invocation.
- Full-stack maintenance of the ViewPoint web application, SilverSky's premier network security monitoring product; technologies included the C# / ASP.NET frontend, Java middleware, and MySQL backend.
- Designed a REST API for internal use to communicate with the asset tracking server (containing customer product info and other account services). Written using Bottle Python web framework, hosted with Docker. This API is still in use today as an important part of the company's managed security service.